Mahesh Y Varpe
OLD BDD Chawal, Block No.A-12
Room No-40, Dahivalkar Buwa Marg
Naigaon Dadar East, Mumbai-400 014

Mb No. 9821836633

Mahesh.varpe@rediffmail.com

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To acquire expertise in the Accounts & system implementation domain experience. Also to obtain a position where I can implement my knowledge, proficiency in the field that will Further give me future growth and Job satisfaction.

SKILLS SUMMARY

More than 21+ years of experience in the field of Account & Finance of FMGC, Manufacturing Machineries, Service Industry, Facility Industry. Real estate Industry

Also, I have exposure to Oracle ERP & Tally ERP-9 and handled the modules like Material Management System – Inventory system & all finance Modules Sales Order System. /CRM, Basic Knowledge of SAP-Finance Module,

STRENGTH

- Excellent team player
- o Excellent Account, Finance, audit & Commercial
- Systematic and analytical approach to any subject
- o Focused & can sustain enthusiasm even in adverse conditions.
- o Short learning cycle and hence easily adaptable to new environments & Situations.
- Ability to delegate.
- o Effective planning & teamwork

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

- B.Com (Bachelor of Commerce) From Pune University in Apr-1998
- DISM (Diploma in Information system Management) From Aptech Institute in Mar 1998.
- DCA (Diploma In Computer Application) June 1995
- CCO (Certificate in Computer Operation) From Mumbai Technical Board in Jan 1996
- MBA FINANCE -Delhi Institute in June 2016

IT SKILLS

Operating Systems : Windows ,XP Language : C, C++, VB

RDBMS : Oracle 8, MS ACCESS

Account Package : Oracle ERP, Tally ERP 9, CRM, FARVISION - ERP

EXPERIENCE

Shreenathji Group

www.shreenathjigroup.co.in

Head –Taxation & Finance 14 June 2019 – Till Date

Company -Builders & Development

Responsibility

Account, Finance & Audit

- Handling 9 companies account up to Balance sheet
- Very good experience in Oracle ERP
- Very good experience in Tally ERP 9
- Preparing Cash Flow
- Dealing with CA/Auditors Audit Co-ordination & Tax Compliances
- Dealing with ROC matters, coordinating with Company Secretary.
- Vendor payment process authorization
- Weekly monitoring of Supplier Outstanding & Ageing Analysis
- Timely fund arrangement for Salary & Compliance (Taxation Payment)

- APF Documentation Checking & Loan Processing.
- Dealing in Business Loan processing of company
- Payroll Checking and Compliance
- Project Finance Dealing with Banks/NBFC, Preparing Project Report with Cash flow.

Taxation

- TDS Compliance
- Service Tax Compliance
- Vat Compliance
- Service Tax Audit Handled
- GST Compliance

Paradigm Group

www.paradigmrealty.co.in

SR. Manager – Account, Taxation & Finance

June 2018 - 12 June 2019 (1.1 Yrs)

Company -Builders & Development

Responsibility

Account, Finance & Audit

- Handling 3 companies account up to Balance sheet
- Very good experience in Farvision
- Very good experience in Tally ERP 9
- Dealing with CA/Auditors Audit Co-ordination & Tax Compliances
- Payment & Bills Approval in Farvision
- Vendor payment process authorization in ENET HDFC Banking
- Weekly monitoring of Supplier Outstanding & Ageing Analysis
- Timely fund arrangement for Salary & Compliance (Taxation Payment)
- Payroll Checking and Compliance
- Preparing Cash Flow Monthly Basic

Shreenathji Group

www.shreenathjigroup.com

Manager – Account & Finance

March 2014 - May 2018(4.2 Yrs)

Company -Builders & Development

Responsibility

Account, Finance & Audit

- Handling 9 companies accounts up to Balance sheet
- Very good experience in Oracle ERP
- Very good experience in Tally ERP 9
- Dealing with CA/Auditors Audit Co-ordination & Tax Compliances
- Dealing with ROC matters, coordinating with Company Secretary.
- Vendor payment process authorization
- Weekly monitoring of Supplier Outstanding & Ageing Analysis
- Timely fund arrangement for Salary & Compliance (Taxation Payment)
- APF Documentation Checking & Loan Processing.
- Dealing in Business Loan processing of company
- Payroll Checking and Compliance
- Project Finance Dealing with Banks/NBFC, Preparing Project Report with Cash flow.

Taxation

- TDS Compliance
- Service Tax Compliance
- Vat Compliance
- Service Tax Audit Handled
- GST Compliance

Allied Resource Management Services India Pvt Ltd (ARMS)

www.armsindia.com

Manager – Accounts & Finance

Jan 2013 - March 2014 (1.3 Yrs.)

Company is Facility Management, Job Work & Skill & Unskilled Manpower, Security Supply

Responsibility:

Account, Finance & Audit

- Handling 3 group of companies accounts up to Balance sheet
- Very good experience in Oracle ERP
- Very good experience in Tally ERP 9
- Payroll Accounting
- Dealing with CA/Auditors Audit Co-ordination & Tax Compliances
- Monthly MRM Presentation of Cash Flow/ P &L statement/ Customer wise Profit Ratio (MIS)
- Vendor payment process authorization
- Weekly monitoring of Customer Outstanding & Ageing Analysis
- Timely fund arrangement for Salary & Compliance (Taxation Payment)
- Weekly meeting With Operation Head, Credit Control Head & account Department.
- Various analytical reports regarding debtors for MIS report.

Taxation

- :
- TDS Compliance.
- Service Tax Compliance
- PF, ESIC, And Professional Tax Compliances

Universal Construction Machinery & Equipment Ltd

www.uceindia.com

Manager - Accounts

June- 2008 - Dec 2012 (4.6 Yrs.)

It is a multi-location widely diversified engineering group manufacturing machineries for Infrastructure and construction Industry

Responsibility:

Functional Area

- Follow up for their outstanding as per their due Date.
- Submit Weekly outstanding list of Debtors to Management
- Verification of daily bank receipts.
- Preparation of MIS reports for weekly meeting like collection, outstanding, Commissioning problems, Cheque bounced any other important issues.
- Preparation for monthly regional meeting like region wise "C" form liability, collection, sales etc.
- Audit co-ordination.
- C form control, corporate co-ordination-visits-reconciliation, Government order, co-ordination, regional account supervision & visits.
- Checking of Dispatch Instruction prepared by Marketing Dept.
- Co-ordination between Marketing & Stores Dept.
- Monthly generation of Ageing Analysis of outstanding for receivables.
- Various analytical reports regarding debtors required for MIS report.
- Monthly Sale tax/Service Tax Return Working Preparation
- Salary TDS Working, Form 16A Quarterly

SALES ACCOUNTING.

- Preparing collection report
- Bank Reconciliation.
- Follow up with concerned Department / Regional Office for monthly closing from viewpoints of MIS
- Reconciliation Customer account Reconciliation along with Customer's statement.
- Take balance Confirmation at year ending
- Outstanding Amount not recovers after long follow-up & 3 Reminder, discuss with seniors to handle that case to legal Dept.
- Passing of Journal vouchers related to Customers accounting.
- Branch Sales monitoring & fund Arrangement
- Branch Reconciliation
- Scrutiny Cheque Report Preparing, Sale registers with Sale summary for monthly return.
- Customer Outstanding & Ageing Analyses.
- Dealer Commission Preparing.

M/s. Malpani Group, Sangamner (Rs.300 Cr turnover Company)

www.malpanigroup.com
Officer – Accounts

Dec 1998 - May 2008 (9.6 Yrs.)

It is a multi-location widely diversified Mfg. of tobacco Responsibility:

Functional Area

- Assist & Handling of accounts up to trial balance (Finalization)
- Preparation Schedules for Balance sheet & Profit & Loss account.
- Reconciliation Account Receivable & intercompany Account
- Bank Reco.
- Implementation in ERP System
- Preparing Supplier Payment

SUNDRY CREDITORS - PURCHASES ACCOUNTING.

- General Accounting
- Printing of Purchase vouchers & printing of purchase register, creditor's ledger.
- Follow up with concerned Department for monthly closing from viewpoints of MIS.
- Reconciliation suppliers account Reconciliation along with supplier's statement.
- Passing of Journal vouchers related to suppliers accounting.
- Branch Purchases & Payments.
- Branch Reconciliation
- Passing Of Purchase Bill
- Scrutiny of Purchase registers with Purchase summary for monthly return.

BANKS - BANK TRANSACTIONS ACCOUNTING.

- Processing of bank payment vouchers related to direct expenses heads, Banking & payment of monthly fixed administrative expenses, weekly passing & payments for site expenses.
- Preparation of Supplier's Payment Vouchers, Accounting of Bank payment vouchers.
- Bank & Cash Payment vouchers approval & authorization.
- Bank Reconciliation For Cash Credit Account & Term Loan Account.
- Preparation of daily Bank Position Statement.
- Making Sundry Creditors Payment Schedule
- All Incoming / outgoing Cheques Control
- Employees Salary Working & Salary JV Accounting
- Payroll Reconciliation

MIS REPORTS -

- Monthly pending Material provision & expenses provision statement.
- Ageing wise analysis report / Bill wise break-up for the month of outstanding Creditors.
- Pending invoices from suppliers for material purchases for the previous month.
- Debtors Outstanding Monitoring & Control

YEARLY & QUARTERLY REVIEWS -

- Preparation of Monthly pending Material Provision & expenses provision statement.
- Sending balance confirmation to suppliers.
- Statement of Open Capital commitment for the year end.
- Finalizing creditors Trail Balance for Qtly / Yearly Reviews.
- Liaoning with auditors for finalizing Audit Reports.
- Any other need based assignment allotted by seniors.

<u>Achievements</u>

- Implementation of Journey Timing System at Malpani Group, Sangamner. <u>Awarded</u> <u>certificate of appreciation for this</u>
- Examiner of "Certificate in Computer Operation (CCO)" of Mumbai Technical Exam Board.

Reference : On Request.

Place : Mumbai

Date :